（火神(かがみ)）ハァ… ハァ… ハァ…
How...
（火神）何で 何でこんなことに
なっちまったんだ？
How did this happen?
Please, somebody...
（火神）頼む 誰か！？
誰か返事をしてくれえ〜！！
Somebody answer me!
2 Hours Earlier
（リコ）よし みんな
準備できたわね？
Okay. Everyone's ready, right?
Let's go.
じゃあ 行こっか？
Crap.
（日向(ひゅうが)）ヤベェ 真冬に
まさか ロッカー室で寝るとか…
I can't believe I fell asleep in a locker room in the middle of winter.
Winter can be so uncool.
（伊月(いづき)）
真冬は まあ不愉快
You're the one who's uncool.
不愉快は オマエだ
（木吉(きよし)）カゼだけは
気をつけないとな
We'd better make sure we don't catch colds.
Hold on, aren't you forgetting something important?
（小金井(こがねい)）ちょっと
大事なこと 忘れてない？
What?
Let's celebrate our victory!
（小金井）祝勝会しようよ〜！
（日向）できるか！！
We can't do that!
What?
（日向）
２回戦はあさって ３回戦以降は
毎日 試合があるんだぞ！
Our second game is the day after tomorrow!
From the third game on, we've got matches every day!
勝っても 浮かれてるヒマなんて
ないっつの！
Even if we win, there's no time to celebrate!
That sounds like a good idea.
（リコ）いーかもね
Let's go get dinner together.
んじゃあ みんなで
行こっか ご飯！
What?
Your recovery is important too.
（リコ）
回復も大切なことだからね
For that, you need to eat properly and get plenty of sleep.
そのためには しっかり食べて
しっかり寝る！
Either way, we intended to go over our next opponent.
どっちにしろ—
あさっての対戦相手の研究も
するつもりだったからな
Where though? Eating out is expensive.
でも どこで？ 外食は高くつくぞ
ん〜 私んちは 遠いしな〜
My place is so far.
Excuse me...
（火神）あの…
（リコ）ん？
My place is actually nearby.
（火神）オレんち こっから
近いんですけど…
What?
shoudou ga atte usoppachi ni idonde
I've got the urge to challenge these bold-faced lies.
boku to kimi to ga shujinkou Love song
You and I are the stars of this love song.
dondon ikimashou
It's time to pick up the pace
Translation Checking: AMS
tsuyoki de semeraretanda
before I lose out to some go-getter,
nakamauchi no warai banashi de wa
and end up like the guys my friends joke about.
Editing: AMS
monmon toshitenda ze
It's starting to drive me crazy...
jibun no heya itsu datte
Always cooped up in my room.
Timing: sangofe
honto wa yowaki na peach mind
The truth is, I've got a timid peach mind
K-Timing: Eternal Blizzard
ki no aru soburi ka
Does she have a thing for me?
Typesetting: AMS, KmE
Karaoke: KmE
tada no omoikomi ka
Or am I reading too much into it?
baretenda ano ko ni wa
Either way, that girl's got us all figured out.
ganbare otoko no ko
Do your best, boys.
Encoding: Your Mom
kono mama ja sanjuugo renpai
If this keeps up, it'll be 35 straight losses.
kimi dake no boku wa Go to guy
But just for you, I'll be your go-to guy.
he
n
ge
ji
za
i
no
ma
ji
ka
ru
su
ta
a
Phantasmagoric magical star
i
da
na
ru
ma
n
ne
ri
da
t
te
i
ja
na
i
What's wrong with a tried-and-true stereotype?
to
me
ro
a
o
sa
wo
Own up to your own inexperience.
ma
da
mi
chi
nu
ko
i
na
ra
ba
If your love has yet to come full circle,
ze
n
bu
a
ge
ru
ze
I'll give you my all.
ki
mi
ni
chi
ka
u
This I swear to you.
saizen-fansubs.com
Episode
Tell Me
（降旗(ふりはた)）ひ…
It's...
広(ひれ)ぇぇぇぇぇ！！
It's huge!
（火神）どうぞ
Come on in.
Kagami, do you live here by yourself?
（土田(つちだ)）火神 ここに
１人で住んでんのか！？
親父と 住む
予定だったんスけど…
I was supposed to live here with my dad.
Kagami, you're a despicable guy after all.
（黒子(くろこ)）火神君って
ヤなヤツだったんですね
ボク もう 影やめます
I'm not going to be your shadow anymore.
Why would you say that?!
（火神）何でだよ！
（日向）しっかし
シンプルな部屋だなぁ
The decor's simple though.
（伊月）
最小限の家具に ボールに雑誌
Minimal furniture, a basketball, and magazines.
You really only think about eating, sleeping, and basketball.
（日向）マジで頭ん中
食う 寝る バスケしかないんだな
Huh? Where's Riko?
あれ？ リコは？
She headed to the kitchen with our ingredients.
（福田(ふくだ)）食材持って
キッチン行きました
You can't be serious!
（日向）
“行きました”じゃねぇぇ！
（伊月）
夏のアレ もう忘れたのか！？
Did you already forget what happened this summer?!
体力回復どころか
死人が出るぞ！
We're not going to recover! We're going to die!
It's ready!
（リコ）できたわよー！
（日向）はっ！！
Highly nutritious.
（リコ）栄養満点！
特製ちゃんこ鍋よ！！
It's my special hot pot.
It's ready...
（部員たち）できちゃった〜
（部員たち）普通… だと！？
It looks normal?
何なのよ もう！
What's wrong with you guys?!
“おいしそう”とか
あるでしょ！？
Can't you say it looks good or something?!
（伊月）ゴメン… 意外すぎて
Sorry, I'm just so surprised.
Well, thanks for the...
（伊月）じゃあ いただきま…
（日向）待て…！
Wait!
Kuroko, you try a bite first.
黒子君 まず一口
食べてごらんよ
The way you're talking is really shady.
（黒子）しゃべり方が
超 怪しいんですけど…
じゃあ すみません お先に…
In that case...
Thanks for the food then.
あれ？
Huh?
Why is there banana in there?
（小金井）何で バナナ入ってんの
It was in the plastic bag.
（リコ）レジ袋の中にあったから
Those were for dessert!
（日向）デザートだよ！
しかも まるごとじゃん！
You put them in whole too!
（リコ）
ダッテ バナナ オイシィ…
But bananas... Yummy...
Why are you speaking like that?!
（伊月）何で カタコトなの！？
てへっ メンゴ メンゴ
Sorry, sorry.
（日向）いつから
そんなキャラになったぁ
When did you start acting like that?!
Don't worry about it, Hyuga.
まあ 気にすんなよ 日向
The rest seems to be normal.
他は普通みたいだし
バナナだけ どけて食べれば…
You can just eat around the bananas.
Why are there strawberries in here?
（小金井）何で イチゴ入ってんの
Because they were in the bag.
（リコ）レジ袋の中にあったから
（日向）だから デザートだよ！！
I told you already! Those were for dessert!
（リコ）ビタミン… トレ
Take vitamins...
（伊月）カタコトで命令形！？
You're giving us orders in broken Japanese now?!
Wait a minute.
（黒子）ちょっと待ってください
（日向･伊月）ええ？
おいしい… かもしれないです
This might actually be good.
He's eating it?!
（部員たち）食ってる！？
（木吉）いける…！
（部員たち）マジで！？
It's not bad.
Seriously?!
Huh?
（小金井）あれ？ こういう
フルーティーな感じも いいかも？
The fruitiness kind of works.
This really isn't too bad.
（伊月）確かに… これはこれで
ええ？ じゃ… じゃあ…
T-Then...
See!
（リコ）えっへん！
（日向）うまい… です
It's good.
（福田）おっ みかんだ！
（河原(かわはら)）も… 桃？
Tangerines!
P-Peaches?!
Cherries?!
（降旗）サクランボ！
ハァ…
Hello.
（黒子）どうも
（火神）ん？
うわぁぁ！ テ テメ… いつから
H-How long have you been there?!
A while.
（黒子）さっきからです
Damn it. I haven't felt that in a while.
くっそ 久し振りだな この感じ
Kagami.
（黒子）火神君
（火神）あ？
What?
今日は ありがとうございました
Thank you for today.
はぁ？ 何だよ 急に
What?! Where did that come from all of a sudden?
I don't know.
分かりません
After the game ended and eating with the guys...
試合が終わって
みんなで ご飯を食べて—
The thought just came to me.
ただ そう思ったんです
I'm really glad I met you, Kagami.
火神君に会えて 本当によかった
Sheesh!
ったく…
You're always saying such embarrassing things.
相変わらず こっぱずかしいこと
しれっと言うな テメーは
You think so?
（黒子）そうですか？
（火神）それに—
Besides, you can't be so carefree forever.
そんな気楽なことばっかり
言ってらんねーぞ
The Winter Cup is only just starting,
ウインターカップは
まだ 始まったばかりだ
but we've already shown everyone almost all our cards.
なのに オレたち誠凛(せいりん)は—
ほぼすべての 手の内
さらけ出しちまった
Our future battles will only be more difficult.
この先 今日よりも
厳しい戦いが続くはずだ
In that case,
（黒子）じゃあ…
（火神）ん？
we'll have to become stronger.
強くなるしかありませんね もっと
Yeah.
ああ そうだな
You're right.
（火神）だあっ…！
黒子 どうしたんだよ？
おい！ うん？
Kuroko?!
What's wrong? Hey!
Guys...
みんなっ…
No...
そんな…
What's going on?!
どーなって…
You have to be kidding me.
（火神）まさか…
Is that even possible?
そんなことが あるのか！？
まるで緩やかに回る
効き目の遅い毒のように…
It's like they've fallen victim to a slow-acting poison.
マズさによるダメージが
遅れてやって来る鍋？
Did the foulness of the hot pot have a delayed effect?!
Death
はうっ！ あ… いっ…
How did she make this with only vegetables and fruits?
（火神）にしても—
野菜や果物だけで
どうやったら こんなことが…？
（火神）だから…
Seriously?
Why did she put supplements in there?
何で サプリメント
入れてんの あの人…！
（日向）ハァ… みんな
帰ったら すぐ寝ろよ
Go to sleep as soon as you get home.
I thought I was going to die.
死ぬかと思った
Kagami, let me use your bathroom.
火神〜 トイレ貸して〜
（火神）出て 右っス
It's out the door and to the right.
ん？ いけね 間違えた
Whoops, wrong room.
（小金井）ふぎゃー！
（日向）ん？ コガ？
Koga?
あ… ああ… あんがぁ…
ん？ おわっ！
You...
（部員たち）おわ〜！！
（火神）うへ…
Who the hell are you?!
（部員たち）
あんたこそ 誰〜！？
Alex? Isn't that...?!
（リコ）アレックス…？
それって確か…
You're training in America until right before the Winter Cup?!
（リコ）ウインターカップ直前まで
アメリカで修行！？
オレにバスケを教えてくれた
師匠がいるんス
I have a master who taught me to play basketball.
Their name is Alex.
名前はアレックス
That's Kagami's master?!
（部員たち）火神の師匠！？
（アレックス）Thanks.
（リコ）アハッ…
（小金井）えー あー
ホワイ ドゥー ユー…
じゃ 日本語でいいぞ
Japanese is fine then.
I majored in it at college, and Taiga taught me some too.
（アレックス）大学で専攻してたし
タイガにも習ったからな
（福田･河原）ハァ…
It's her.
（伊月）いた！
（木吉）ん？
Alexandra Garcia.
（伊月）
アレクサンドラ＝ガルシア…
She was a college state champion.
向こうの大学バスケの
州チャンピオン
She later played in the WNBA.
その後 ＷＮＢＡでプレーしてる
（河原）ＷＮＢＡって
女子のプロ！？
The WNBA? She's a pro?
Seriously?
（福田）マジで？
I already retired though.
（アレックス）もう引退したけどな
（木吉）え？
My eyesight was ruined by an illness.
病気で 視力が著しく落ちてね
今は地元の小さなクラブチームで
コーチとして バスケを教えてる
Now I just coach a little club team.
それで 何で日本に…？
What are you doing in Japan though?
あっ カントク！ あんま
その人に近づくと…！
Coach, don't get so close!
What?
う〜ん 日本の女子は
キュートだねえ
Japanese girls are so cute.
What?!
キス魔…
She's got a kissing bug!
I told you.
だから…
Don't do that to everyone!
誰彼 構わず
そういうこと すんなよ！
What are you talking about?!
何言ってんだ！
私がすんのは女子供だけだ！
I only kiss girls and children!
I'm not asking about your kissing policy!
ポリシー聞いてねぇよ！！
So, why did you come to Japan?
それで 何で日本に
来たんですか？
Huh? Oh...
How long have you been sitting there?!
（アレックス）
オマエ いつから いた！？
I was here all along.
（黒子）最初からいました
Seriously?
（アレックス）ホントか！？
って… あ〜！
オマエが タイガの言ってた
Oh, you're that guy Taiga mentioned.
I see.
なるほどな
Taiga and Tatsuya.
（アレックス）タイガとタツヤ
I came to see my two apprentices play basketball.
愛弟子２人の試合を
観にきたんだ バスケのね
By Tatsuya, do you mean...?
タツヤって もしかして…
That guy from Yosen you met at the street ball tournament?
ストバスで会ったっていう
陽泉(ようせん)の？
Did he learn how to play basketball from you too, Alex?
（降旗）あの人もアレックスさんに
バスケを教わってたんですか？
引退後は まだ
事実を受け止められずに—
After I retired, I couldn't accept my reality and was acting out.
私も荒れててね
I played on street courts to vent my frustration.
うっぷん晴らしに
ストリートのコートに通ってた
One day
そんなある日—
this guy and Tatsuya asked me to take them on as apprentices out of nowhere.
突然 コイツとタツヤが—
“弟子にしてくれ！”とか
言ってきたんだ
As first, I was reluctant.
最初はしぶしぶだった
But...
けど…
Before I knew it,
気がつけば…
私も笑ってバスケをしていた
I was playing basketball with a smile.
その２人が成長して 日本で再び
戦うってんだ 気にもなるさね
Those two have grown up and are facing each other again here in Japan.
Of course I'm curious.
Actually, we don't know that they'll face each other yet.
でも まだ 戦うって
決まってませんよ
（アレックス）What？
On top of that, we don't have a game tomorrow, so we're just watching.
（土田）しかも明日は試合ないから
オレたちは観戦だけですけど
Really?
（アレックス）あれ そーなの？
I'll go with you then! Take me with you!
じゃ 私も一緒に行く！
連れてってくれ！
Kuroko's
I
Basketball
（アレックス）おーおー
やるなぁ おい！
Hey, not bad.
Honestly, I wasn't expecting much from Japanese basketball.
正直 日本のバスケを
ナメてたとこ あったんだが—
I'd better apologize for that one.
謝らなきゃならねーな こりゃ
サイズとパワーは
物足りないが—
They're lacking in size and power,
but their speed and strategies are impressive.
スピードと戦略は十分に
見応えあるな
それに 選手１人１人も
なかなか ツブぞろいじゃねーの
Furthermore, every player is excellent too.
特に 今 コートに出てきた７番
Especially that No. 7 guy who just came onto the court.
They made it to the top four in the Inter-High last year.
去年インターハイ
ベスト４まで行った—
That's Kobayashi Keisuke of Onita High.
大仁多(おおにた)高の小林圭介(こばやしけいすけ)
At 188 centimeters, he's an unusually tall point guard for Japan.
188センチの 日本じゃ珍しい
長身ポイントガード
He's an all-rounder who can pass and score.
パスも出せて 点もとれる
オールラウンダー
He's one of the best players in the country.
全国でも屈指の選手だ
He's got something special.
（アレックス）あいつは
いいもん持ってる 相当やるな
He's pretty good.
だが—
But...
His opponent today is...
今日の相手は…
Shutoku
Onita
（日向）ハァ…
I can never get used to watching the Generation of Miracles play.
ったく“キセキの世代”の試合は
何度 観ても慣れんな
Honestly, it's depressing.
正直 気が滅入るぜ
Every school was chosen from its prefecture for its strength.
（木吉）すべてのチームが
各県から選ばれた強豪だ
弱いはずがない
しかし その中でも—
None of them are weak.
However, teams with members from the Generation of Miracles are exceptional.
“キセキの世代”のいるチームは
やはり ずば抜けている
They make veterans indistinguishable from ordinary players.
全国の猛者(もさ)が
凡百と変わらず かすむほどに…
We know that.
そんなこと 百も承知よ！
Besides, the most important thing is our next game.
それに 何より大事なのは
まず 次の試合
Let's head home and review the data on Nakamiya South.
帰って中宮南(なかみやみなみ)のデータを
おさらいするわよ！
（部員たち）おう！
Yeah!
About that...
（アレックス）あー それなんだが
（火神）ん？ んおっ！
（火神）おっ… おい！
（アレックス）悪いが—
Hey!
Sorry, but could I borrow this guy for a while?
コイツをしばらく
貸してもらえないかな？
I'll make sure he's back in time for your next game.
（アレックス）
次の試合には間に合わせる
頼む
Please.
What was that about, Alex?
（火神）
何だよ アレックス いきなり…
The Generation of Miracles you mentioned...
（アレックス）オマエの言ってた
“キセキの世代”
I didn't expect them to be that good.
まさか あそこまでとは
思ってなかった
They're monsters.
ありゃ 確かにバケモンだ
Since you've beaten one, as long as you don't
その１人を倒した
オマエらなら—
underestimate your opponents, you should easily win your second and third games.
油断さえなけりゃ
２〜３回戦も 問題はないはずだ
However, it's unfortunate you'll have to face Yosen after that.
だが—
そのあとに当たる
陽泉ってのは 分が悪すぎる
Not only do they have one monster,
ただでさえバケモノが
１人いる上に—
but after you returned to Japan,
タイガが日本に帰ったあと—
タツヤは私の教えを得て
ストリートで技を磨いてきた
Tatsuya polished his street ball skills under my tutelage.
You could say he's on par with one of those monsters now.
今のあいつは そのバケモンと
ほぼ 同格と言っていい
As a result of his training,
さらに言えば その結果—
今のタツヤとオマエの相性は
この上なく悪い
your matchup with Tatsuya couldn't be worse.
口出しする気はなかったが
ちと フェアじゃない
I wasn't going to say anything, but it's not quite fair.
I don't know how much we can do in a couple of days,
１日 ２日で
どこまでできるか分からんが…
オマエには まだ
教え残していることがある
but there's something I haven't taught you yet.
Huh? Where's Kuroko?
（土田）あれ 黒子は？
Now that you mention it...
そういえば…
どうも
Hello.
Don't give me that.
（青峰(あおみね)）“どうも”じゃねーよ
Why'd you suddenly call me out here, Tetsu?
いきなり呼び出して
どういうつもりだ テツ
Let me be direct.
単刀直入に言います
青峰君
Aomine...
Teach me to shoot, please.
ボクに シュートを教えてください
He went to have Aomine teach him to shoot?
（伊月）青峰にシュートを
教わりに行ったぁ！？
As far as I know, he's the best.
ボクが知る限り
一番うまいのは 彼ですから
As far as he knows?
（土田）知る限りっつーか
誰が見てもそうだが… 大丈夫か？
It's plain to see he is, but...
Is he going to be okay?
Even if he does teach him, can he really learn anything in a couple of days?
だいたい 仮に
教えてくれたとしても—
１日 ２日で身につくのか？
１日 ２日じゃないわ
It's not a couple of days.
そもそもシュートの練習は
予選のあと—
He's been practicing his shooting with my dad since after the preliminaries.
パパがコーチについた時から
やってたのよ
I told him about the wall he's likely to hit soon.
（景虎(かげとら)）あいつが おそらく
この先 ぶち当たるであろう壁
…については もう伝えた
He must have been referring to his shooting.
（リコ）
それはつまり シュートのことよ
確かに シュート力が
低いままじゃ—
Yeah, if he doesn't learn to shoot,
his Vanishing Drive will eventually lose its usefulness.
いずれ バニシングドライブは
使えなくなる
What? Why?
え？ 何で？
Actually, if you think about it, it's pretty obvious.
（木吉）まあ ちょっと考えれば
しごく当たり前のことなんだが—
After Kuroko penetrates the defense with his drive,
黒子がドライブで
ペネトレイトして—
ヘルプが来て
空いたスペースにパス
someone comes to stop him, creating an opening for a pass.
That's how it's worked until now.
これが今までの基本パターン
だが もし敵が
ヘルプに来なかったら—
However, if no one comes to stop him,
Kuroko has to make the shot himself.
黒子は自らシュートを
打たなければならない
In other words, breaking through with a drive
（木吉）つまりドライブで
斬り込むってことは—
becomes truly threatening when you can make the shot yourself.
自分で決める力があって
初めて 本当の脅威になる
Against Shutoku and Kirisaki,
we only used it a few times, so it worked.
（リコ）秀徳(しゅうとく)戦 霧崎(きりさき)戦では
数度しか使わなかったから—
ボロが出なかったし—
Against Touou, Aomine defeated the drive itself.
桐皇(とうおう)戦では青峰君に—
ドライブそのものを
破られてしまった
けど 黒子君のシュート率の
悪さがバレれば—
However, if anyone should discover Kuroko's awful shooting percentage,
our opponents would do what Teppei just said.
鉄平(てっぺい)の言ったことを
敵がしてくるのは 必然よ
On top of that, his Overflow is our trump card.
それに オーバーフローは
あくまで切り札
It won't work twice against the same opponent,
対戦相手に 二度と
使えないのはもちろん—
and it loses its effectiveness against teams who have seen it.
見られたチームに対しても
効果が薄くなっていくから—
If we use it too much, we'll be digging our own graves.
乱発すれば 自分の
首をしめていく一方だわ
Things have gotten out of order, but either way,
順序が多少
変わってしまったけど—
どちらにしろ
この先を戦うには—
Kuroko needs to improve his shooting for future battles.
黒子君のシュート力アップは
必要不可欠ってことね
How was that?
（黒子）どうですか？
（青峰）知らねぇよ！！
You can't be serious!
Did you think I'd be happy getting dragged out here and shown your crappy shooting?!
ムリヤリ連れてきて
ヘボシュート見せて—
どうもこうもあるか！
I never said I'd teach you to shoot!
教えるなんて
ひと言も言ってねーだろが！
Why not?
何でですか？
There's something wrong with someone who beats a guy and asks him to teach him how to shoot the next day!
負かした相手に翌日—
シュート教えろっつってくるほうが
どうかしてるわ！
I haven't slept since then.
寝てねーんだよ あれから
What?
I went home, ate, took a bath,
（青峰）あれから帰って—
メシ食って フロ入って
そんで 横になった
then I went to lie down.
But I couldn't sleep.
けど いつまでたっても
寝れやしねえ
My body was exhausted,
体はヘトヘトなのに—
but when I closed my eyes, I saw scenes from the game.
目をつぶれば
試合のシーンが浮かぶんだ
ずっと忘れていた あの感じ
I had forgotten how that felt.
My chest feels tight, I feel nauseous like I'm going to puke,
胸がしめつけられて—
吐き気みたいな
むかつきがあって—
頭がガンガンする
and my head is pounding.
Since I forgot about it, I kind of missed it,
忘れかけて
懐かしんではみたものの—
but now that I've experienced it again, I don't miss it at all.
いざまた味わってみれば
何のことはねぇ—
It still just sucks.
結局 変わらず苦いだけだ
It was an awful night.
最悪の夜だったぜ
But
けど—
that's why I want to play basketball again so soon.
だからこそ今は バスケが
早くしたくて しょうがねえ
青峰君
Aomine...
（青峰）
あーあ 話してたら—
Oh, man.
Talking about it made me want to play.
何かマジでバスケ
やりたくなってきたわ
I can't help myself, so I'll play with you.
しょうがねえから
付き合ってやるよ
I'm saying I'll teach you to shoot.
シュート教えてやるっつってんだよ
（青峰）何 笑ってんだよ
What are you smiling about?
We used to practice like this a lot in middle school.
いえ 中学の時も
よくこうして 練習してましたね
（青峰）んん…
いいから とっとと打て！
Just hurry up and shoot!
You said you don't have much time!
時間ねーんだろ！！
ハァ…
I still feel a little tired.
（火神）さすがに疲れは残るか…
I was up late training with Alex after all.
深夜までアレックスの
特訓だったからな
But in order to keep winning, I need to become stronger.
けど この先も勝つには—
もっと強くならなきゃ
なんねえんだ
やるしかねぇ…！
There's no other way.
お？ おはよう よく眠れたか？
Morning. Did you sleep well?
I told you to put on some clothes!
だから 服 着ろっつってんだろ！！
Yeah, but don't throw clothes at me!
だから 服 投げつけんじゃねぇ！
ったく…
Sheesh...
We may've trained a little too hard between his games.
（アレックス）
さすがに試合の合間に—
この練習量は ちと厳しいか
だが 時間は限られている
We don't have much time though.
How much he'll learn depends not on Taiga's stamina,
どこまで モノにできるかは
体力以上に—
タイガの精神力に かかっている
but on his mental strength.
National High School Basketball
Championship Tournament
Opening Ceremony
The third day of the Winter Cup.
（リコ）ウインターカップ ３日目
Over the first and second days, every first-round game was completed.
初日と２日目で
１回戦 全試合を消化
The 50 participating schools were reduced by nearly half to 32.
出場校 50校は およそ半分の
32校へと絞られた
（日向）行くぞ！
（部員たち）おう！！
Let's go!
Yeah!
（リコ）そして２回戦
The second round of games.
Along with the seeded schools,
the remaining 32 schools gather on the court.
ここからシード校も参戦し—
生き残った32校すべてが
会場に集結
On this day, in 16 games, all the teams will clash.
この日 １日で 16試合
全チームが激突する
Our opponent's strength is a slow, half court game.
いい！？ 相手は じっくり
時間をかけて攻める—
ハーフコートバスケットが
得意なチームよ
It's not a good matchup for a fast-paced team like ours,
早い展開を好むウチとは
相性が悪いから—
so we'll change our starting lineup and see how things go.
まずはメンツを変えて
様子を見るわ
Hyuga!
日向君！ 伊月君！ 鉄平！
Izuki!
Teppei!
Mitobe!
水戸部(みとべ)君！ 土田君！
Tsuchida!
These five will be our starters!
スタートは
この５人でいくわよ！
Yeah!
（部員たち）おう！！
Hey, don't look so worried right before the game.
こら いっちょ前に
心配そうなツラしてんなよ！
I'm not worried.
してません
Then let me hear you!
（日向）
なら ちゃんと声 出せえ！！
Yeah!
（火神）うす！
（黒子）はいっ！
The fifth Winter Cup match between
（審判）それではこれより
ウインターカップ 第５試合—
Seirin High and Nakamiya South High will now begin!
誠凛高校 対 中宮南高校の
試合を始めます！
Bow!
礼！！
Let's have a good game!
（選手たち）
よろしくお願いします！
kasunda mirai wo kirisaku you ni terasu hikari
Like a shining light that cuts through the hazy future,
musuu no kanousei wo motome
I chase after unlimited possibilities.
Gotta open my eyes
Wake up sabitsuita me ni hi wo tomose
Wake up, light a fire in your tired eyes.
Get up kusubutteru baai ja nainda zettai
Get up! Now's definitely not the time to let it smoulder.
youi sareta risou nante iranai
You don't need to have some big dream.
yuragu koto no nai ishi to
Just an unwavering spirit,
mikansei na chizu de ii kara
and an unfinished map is enough.
asu wo tsukame kono te de
Hold on to tomorrow with these hands!
detarame na rizumu de nurikaete iku kako ni
Regretting a past that's being overwritten by a nonsensical rhythm...
koukai hitotsu arienai daro
That's not possible, right?
ari no mama no biito de kurikaeshite iku genzei wo
I'll rewrite things with the true beat now,
kasaneta mirai kagayaku you ni
and create a sparkling future.
kizami konda sonzai wo kesshou toshite
Your existence is etched as a crystal.
Keep it in my story
Next Episode
Their second game should be starting soon.
（諏佐(すさ)）そろそろ
二回戦 始まる頃だよな
Seirin, huh?
（今吉(いまよし)）誠凛か まあ
本調子とは いかへんやろなあ
Well, they probably won't hit their stride.
What do you mean?
（諏佐）どういう意味だ？
If they let it get to their heads, it's over.
（今吉）
勝って兜(かぶと)の緒を絞めよってな
If they let their guard down, they'll lose.
油断したら負けるで
Let their guard down, huh?
（諏佐）油断か… ん？
Episode
Of Course It's Not Easy
Imayoshi, you suck at drawing.
（諏佐）今吉… 絵 下手くそだな
（今吉）だはっ…